Guide to the Wanda Gifford Photographs 1948-1958
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Wanda Gifford Photographs
1948-1958
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
P 218-SG 4
Gifford, Wanda.
2 cubic feet, including 3670 photographs 15 boxes, including 2 oversize boxes, and 1 map folder
The Wanda Gifford Photographs consist of images taken by Wanda Gifford during the late 1940s and 1950s that document post-war Salem, Oregon; agriculture in the Willamette Valley; and scenic views of Oregon landmarks, the northern Cascades in Washington, Glacier National Park in Montana. After Ralph Gifford's death in 1947, his wife Wanda Muir Gifford took over the family's photography business and continued to take and sell photographs through the mid-1950s.
Biographical Note:
After Ralph Gifford's death in 1947, his wife, Wanda Muir Gifford (1894-1989) took over the family's photography business. Wanda, born in Florin, California, was a 1916 Oregon Agricultural College home economics graduate. She taught home economics in the Portland schools for several years. Ralph and Wanda Gifford had two sons, Ralph Arthur Gifford, who attended Oregon State College before his death in 1939, and Ben L., who carried on the family's photographic tradition for a third generation.
Wanda took and sold photographs from 1947 through the mid-1950s. Largely self-taught in photography, she worked primarily on weekends -- in addition to her job with the County Clerk's office in the Marion County Courthouse. "As Mr. Gifford preferred to photograph landscapes, I am very much interested in child photography," she wrote to a magazine editor about a year after Ralph's death. "With all those fine cameras and a complete laboratory left me I must carry on." Wanda also took many photographs of agriculture subjects, and as Ralph had done, marketed the family's photographs to trade publications, such as American Fruit Grower and U.S. Camera magazines, newspapers, advertising firms, and corporations.
Wanda retired from the Marion County Clerk's office in 1958 and lived in Salem for most of the remainder of her life. She died in Sublimity, Oregon, in 1989.
The Wanda Gifford Photographs were taken by Wanda Gifford during the late 1940s and 1950s and document the changing face of post-war Salem, Oregon; agriculture in the Willamette Valley; and scenic views of Oregon landmarks, Mount Baker and the northern Cascades in Washington, and Glacier National Park in Montana. The collection also includes images of family and friends and portrait photographs of individuals, family groups, and special occasions such as weddings and anniversaries. Children were one of Wanda Gifford's favorite subjects. Numerous images of snow scenes in the Willamette Valley are included in the collection.
Oregon landmarks that are depicted in the collection include Mount Hood, the Oregon Coast, Multnomah Falls, the Wallowa Mountains, and Steens Mountain. Agricultural images include orchards, strawberry fields, dairy herds, and other livestock. Of special note are numerous images of Mary Kueny and the Kueny Ranch in southeastern Oregon near Steens Mountain. Photographs of the Detroit Dam are also included.
The images of Salem, Oregon, include the original Marion County Courthouse, the Oregon State Capitol and other state buildings, churches, businesses and street scenes, schools, and homes. The courthouse photographs include interior and exterior views and images of offices and workers in the building.
The majority of items in the collection are 4x5 and 120 format film negatives; accompanying prints are included for about a third of the negatives. There are only a few prints without accompanying film negatives. A small percentage of the 4x5 negatives are diacetate-based that are degraded and in poor condition; these are housed separately. The collection also includes 96 color transparencies, primarily 4x5 format. Some of the color transparencies were probably made by Ben L. Gifford.
A selection of images from the collection are available online in The Best of the Archives and other digital collections.
Collection is open for research.
The Wanda Gifford Photographs are arranged in 3 series: I. Numbered Photographs, 1948-1957; II. Unnumbered Photographs, 1949-1958; and III. Color Transparencies, circa 1950s.
The photographs were donated to the Oregon State University Horner Museum in 1986 by Ben L. and Beth Gifford.
The photographs were transferred from the Oregon State University Horner Museum to the University Archives in July 1996.
This is one component of the Gifford Photographic Collection (P 218) held by the OSU Archives. Other components are: Benjamin A. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 1); Ralph I. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 2); Ralph I. Gifford Motion Pictures (P 218-SG 3); Ben L. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 5); Gifford Collection Photographs by Unknown or Other Photographers (P 218-SG 6); and Gifford Collection Documentary Materials (P 218-SG 7).
Other images of Salem, Oregon, are available in the Walter R. Baker Photographs (P 018), Oliver Matthew Photographs (P 118), and Oliver Matthews Collection.
Gifford, Ben L.
Marion County (Or.); Oregon State Capitol (Salem, Or.: 1938- )
Agriculture--Oregon.; Lakes--Oregon.; Landscape photography--Oregon.; Parks--Oregon.; Portrait photography--Oregon.
Baker, Mount (Wash.); Cascade Range.; Detroit Dam (Or.); Glacier National Park (Mont.); Hood, Mount (Or.); Multnomah Falls (Or.); Oregon--Description and travel.; Pacific Coast (Or.); Salem (Or.); Steens Mountain (Or.); Wallowa Mountains (Or.)
Color transparencies.; Film negatives.; Photographic prints.
Agriculture; Children and Youth; City and Town Life; Home and Family; Parks and Playgrounds; Ranching; Sports and Recreation; Women; Montana; Oregon; Washington (State); Corvallis; Salem; Photographs
- Numbered Photographs, 1948-1957; Series I; 1946 negatives and 884 prints
  Series I comprises most of the Wanda Gifford Photographs and consists of images made by Wanda Gifford in the late 1940s through mid-1950s. The photographs depict Salem, Oregon, in the post-war years; agriculture, especially in the Willamette Valley; children and families; Oregon scenes, especially Mount Hood and the Oregon coast; the Steens Mountains; North Cascades; Glacier National Park; and the Grand Tetons. Agricultural images include orchards, strawberry fields, dairy herds, and other livestock. Of special note are numerous images of the Kueny Ranch in southeastern Oregon and Mary Kueny. Most of the negatives are 4x5 and 120 format; several of the 4x5 negatives are diacetate-based that are in poor condition.
  - Lidbeck home; front view, 0001; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Lidbeck home from road; long shot, 0002; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    time 1/100 at F16; telephoto lens
  - Lidbeck home; terrace, 0003; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    Telephoto lens; time 1/25 at F11; graphic view.
  - Lidbeck home, gate, horse, & drive horse, 0004; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    lens curl lies back lighting; 1/100 at F5.6; exposed for shadow; 4:30 pm; tripod used; g. view
  - Lidbeck home; late afternoon, 0005; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Maryln Colgan and blossoms, 0006; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Linda Williams and apple blossoms, 0007-0009
    - 0007, print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    - 0008, 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    - 0009, 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Linda Williams; apple blossoms, 0010; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    Best negative.
  - Harold Stassen on Court House steps, Salem, Oregon, 1948; 0011-0012; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    speed graphic 1/100 between F8 and 11; cloudy day; aktar lens; 127 mm; S pan press D 60A
  - Meyer Glove Co. on 12th St., 0013; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    Taken late afternoon;g. view on tripod; K1 filter.
  - Tractor and hay wagon, Guy Shields home, Rt. 5; close up, 0014; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    graphic; 1/100 F11; K1 filter and lens shade; bright day-blue sky-clouds
  - Hay wagon and tractor, Guy Shield home, 0015; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    graphic; 1/100 at F16; filter K1-shade on lens; bright day afternoon early
  - Hay baler; long shot, 0016; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    graphic; filter; lens shaded; 1/100 F11
  - Hay baler; close up, 0017; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    graphic; 1/100 at F11
  - Colgan boy and Gibson tractor, 0018-0019; 2 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    Plowing young walnut orchard with Gibson tractor.
  - Silver Creek Falls, 0020; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/10 sec at F8
  - Yvonne and Harry Winkler at Silver Creek, late afternoon in June, 0021; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Harry and Yvonne Winkler in Gifford back yard, 0022-0023; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Ladd's Market, South 12th St., 0033; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    6 counts
  - Super portrait group, 0034; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Baby Hagedorn, 0035; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    6 counts on cykora; shade right baby side; give hall on right extra
  - Baby Hagedorn and birthday cake, 0036; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    12 counts with cykora no. 3 give 3 extra to cake
  - County clerk group, 0037; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1 and 2+ counts; late evening 1 flush; 1/100 F 5.6
  - Lidbeck home, 0041; 1 print and 8 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
  - Bridge over Santiam River, 0043; 2 prints of one negative; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
  - Clouds, 0045; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Camellia Society, 0047; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Post Office; Methodist Church on State St., 0048; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Church on Court Street, 0049; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Oregon State Capitol from across plaza, 0050; 5 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Eva Baynerd on bridge stairs, 0051; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Yvonne home, etc, 0052; 7 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Oregon mill town, Gardner, near coast; taken from Highway 101, 0053; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Ocean from Crissey's, Brookings, Oregon, 0054; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Boiler Bay, Oregon coast, 0055; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Garden shots at Iufer's, 0056; 1 print and 3 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
  - Sunsets; Hop house, 0057; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Woman playing with cat, 0059; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Approaching storm, 0060; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    5 counts; barn house silhouette
  - Humbug Mountain, Oregon coast, 0061; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    gray day; desolation; 4 to 6 counts; F3 paper; print in clouds
  - Oregon coast from Crissey's, Brookings, Oregon, 0062; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    print in sky and foreground; about 4 to 6 counts for center
  - Evening shadows; country road, 0065; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Swimming hole, river, 0066; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Mt. Hood, Laurel Hill, 0068; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    S. graphic; set film speed at 50 used K3 filter; took brightness reading; shot at 1/50 at F16
  - Mt. Hood, Laurel Hill; bus on highway, 0069; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Highway 99, south of Salem, 0070; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Lindsey, 0071; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Rombo boy and calf; 40 Evergreen Ave., Salem, 0072; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Clayton Rombo with lamb in arms and lamb nursing, 0073; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    9 counts for bath negatives no. 2 paper F5.6
  - Oregon coast from Crisseys' Porch; Iris in corner, 0074; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    6 counts; F3
  - Linda and apple blossoms, 0075; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Linda and apple blossoms, 0076; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Linda, laughing, and apple blossoms, 0077; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Homeward bound; fishing boats at Depoe Bay, 0080; 4 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Homeward bound; fishing boats at Depoe Bay, 0081; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Bridge cathedrals, 0082; 4x5 negative and oversize print (Box 9, 76)
    Mounted print on verso of image 0784.
  - Deserted bench, Capitol Park, 5 o'clock September 28, 1948; 0083; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    speed graphic light reading; taken on grass in sunlight; set C position in reading Reading 1 block above 25; 1/100 at F 4.7 back lighting
  - Salem street scenes taken after rainy night, December 13 1948; 0084; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    10 counts at F8 and one inch and 10 counts at F6.3; lights over exposed
  - Registering voters Presidential Election 1948; long shot, 0085; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/100 at F16; SP graphic; little under timed
  - Harlan Judd at his desk, 1948; 0086; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Anna Testo typing, 0087; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/200 at F16; 10 ft. GE no 5
  - Alyce and Muriel only over exposed; election shots in court house, 0088; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/100 at F16; 10 ft.; too much exposure; Anna 1/200, better exposure 10 ft.; long shot; little under at 1/100 at F 16
  - Randalls at gate, 0089; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
    1/100 at F11; late evening light
  - Randall's guest house inside, 0090; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/50 at F16 with 1 no 5 GE about 15 ft from ?
  - Independence Bridge construction; cloudy day, 0091; 10 prints and 4 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    shot all at 100 at F8; shot one showing bridge end at 1/50 at F 6.3; had K2 filter on end shots
  - Yohuel negatives, 0092; 4 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
    1 flush then 3 counts; F 11 shade over art while country 3
  - Garnet Sixes children, 0093; 5 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Getty, 0094; 5 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Francis at the mail box, Salem, December 23, 1948; 0095; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
    1/100 at F8; bright clear day, cold; speed graphic
  - Clerk groups, December 14, 1948; 0096; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    Sp. graphic; 5 counts overall; barn in foreground; 1/50 at F16; 2 no. 22 GE buibs; me at camera in a 20 ft extension to right; walls cream, large room; about 25 ft from nearest ?
  - Recorder group Christmas party, 0097; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    5 counts over all then a bot of burning in Edma (?) and (?) also on desk in corner
  - Edna on (?) house steps, 0098; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    3 counts
  - My garden path, 0099; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - State Street (Salem), September 30, 1948 at 8 am; 0100; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/100 at F8; speed graphic
  - Salem Crown Willamette? mill taken from across river, noon time, September 30, 1948; 0101; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/100 at F16 K2 filter speed graphic
  - Crown Willamette mill; river and logs, October 16, 1948; 0102; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    S. graphic; 1/100 at F11; no filter; about 3:30 pm
  - Sunshine farm; white face herefords at Roberts, Oregon, about 4 pm, October 16, 1948; 0103; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    1/101 at F8; late light; no filter print
  - Rosemay Howard, October 25, 1948; 0104; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
    1/100 at F11; taken S. graphic about 2:30 pm, print 3 1/2 counts
  - View from Tualatin farm; taken late afternoon, October 1948; 0105; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Wilsonville Ferry, October 23, 1948; 0106; 2 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    Taken about 11:30 am.
  - Dot Gamble; test shower, 0107; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/100 at F16; about 10 ft away
  - Grain field under overhanging tree, 0108; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Alders and hay corks, 0109; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Colgan children carving pumpkin, 0110; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Fields with a mountain in the background, 0122 (Box 4)
  - Cheryl on Banks of Santiam; "Dirty Hands", 0123; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Baby Hagedorn with a candle, 0124; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
    1/100 at F22
  - Baby Hagedorn, 0125; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
    1/200 at F22; standing on head
  - Janet Hagedorn at 15 months, 0126; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    flash; 1/200 at between 22-32; speed graphic; s. pan press
  - Baby Hagedorn with candle, 0127; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Jeanette Hagedorn at 15 months, 0128; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    flash; 1/200 at 22-32; speed graphic; s. pan press
  - Covered bridge near Willamette, Oregon, crosses Tualatin River, 0129; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Sheep at Dickman farm, Oregon City, Oregon, 0130; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Long shot; sheep at Dickman farm, 0131; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Close up of Hampshire ewe at Dickman farm, 0132; print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 4, 67)
  - Bill Dickman feeding sheep from pail, 0133; 3 prints and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 4, 67)
  - Bill Dickman holding lamb, 0134; print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 4, 67)
  - Lambs digging for feed, 0135; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Group of lambs; Dickman farm, 0136; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Three faces; sheep, 0137; print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 4, 67)
  - Snow shot at Mt. Hood, 0138; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
    can use portion for Christmas card
  - Mt. Hood taken at Timberline (use only portion), 0139; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Skiers and lift, Mt. Hood (use portion), 0140; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Birch row, Salem, Oregon, 0141; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Pauline's little girl, 0142; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Dunigan Bridge close up, 0143; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Dunigan Bridge long shot, 0144; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Mill stream, Turner, Oregon (use portion), 0145; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Dairy herd near Gresham, Oregon (use portion), 0146; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Parade shots, Salem, Oregon, 0147; 2 prints and 4 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
  - 12th St. Food Market, Salem, 0148; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Ivy on church steeple, Methodist church, Salem, 0149; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Bendix Launderette on Trade St. near state heating plant, 0150; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Children on Lions Club statue, 0151; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Annetta Judd, 0152; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Ducks on Mill Race, 0153; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Ducks on Mill Race, 0154; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Ducks at penitentiary, 0155; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Zelda at turn around, Seaside, Oregon, 0156; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Forestry Building, Salem, Oregon, 0157; print 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    See also color transparencies.
  - Pinkie babe Neal Hagedorn, 0159; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Flying along road in car; farm in background, 0160; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Snell hall floor plans, 0165; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - South Falls during 1948-49 snow, January; taken at base of falls, 0166; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - South Falls during 1948-49 snow, January; taken at base of falls, 0167; print and 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - South Silver Creek Falls; snow, 1948-1949; 0168; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - South Falls during 1948-49 snow, January 1949; 0169; 6 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Silver Creek; snow; V tree, 1948-1949; 0170; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Silver Creek during snow, 1948-1949; 0171; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Ice flow in Silver Creek, Silver Falls State Park, Oregon, 0172; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    Speed Graphic; K1 filter; 1/100 F16; Super Pan Press film developed in D 60 A
  - Silver Creek, back lighted in winter, 0173; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    Graphic Speed; K1 filter 1/100 at F11; Super Pan Press; D 60A development 6 min.; printed on Kodabromide No 3
  - Lone oak tree, 0174; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Christmas 1948; Cherie, Beth, cat, 0178; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Cherie, Beth, 0179; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Coast line, 0180; 2 prints (Box 4)
  - Mary's River and walkway, Corvallis (Avery?) Park, 0181; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Boat house on Mary's River, Corvallis (Avery?) Park, 0182; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Boat house and rocks, Mary's River, Corvallis (Avery?) Park, 0183; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Boat house and alders, Corvallis (Avery?) Park, 0184; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Entrance to Corvallis (Avery?) Park, 0185; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Horse and sleigh, Corvallis, 0186; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Feller boy with lamb nursing, 0187; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Feller boy with lamb in arms, 0188; 4x5 negative and oversize mounted print (Box 9, 76)
  - A Caesarian lamb whose mother was killed by a dog, raised by Freddie Feller, age 13, on a bottle, Salem, Oregon (burn in hat; burn in snow), 0189; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Erwin Ward and his dog, 0190; 2 4x5 diacetate negatives (Box 67)
  - Feller boy and his lamb with a male cat on his shoulder, 0191; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Street scenes at Christmas time, Salem, Oregon, 0192; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Willamette Bridge; long shot, 0194; 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 67)
  - Willamette covered bridge with dusting of snow; medium shot, 0195; 2 prints and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 4, 67)
  - "A Basket full of Wool"; Dickman lambs in basket, 0196; print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 4, 67)
  - Dickman sheep in snow; big ears, 0197; print and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 9, 67)
  - Feeding hay; Dickman sheep in shed, 0198; 3 prints and 4x5 diacetate negative (Box 9, 67)
  - Sheep on way to Silver Creek Falls, 0199; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Ben Newall's children, 0200; 4 4x5 diacetate negatives (Box 67)
  - Section of 99E out of Salem, 0201; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Roberts Home, S. 12th St., Salem, Oregon, in snow, 1949; 0202; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    s. graphic; 1/100 at F16; about 8 am, February 7, 1949; s. pan press; RK60A K2 filter; D72?
  - Peterson Home, S. 12th, in snow, 1949; 0203; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
    s.p. graphic; 1/100 at F16; 8 am, February 7, 1949; K2 filter
  - Snow shots taken at home N.G., 0204; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
    Use cloud effect on other negs.
  - Cherie and Beth pouring tea, 0205; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
    1/200 at F32; under exposed bad shadow; not good
  - Bedroom, 0206; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1 sec. at F32; flood lights 1 no 4 in corner to left; 1 ssp on floor; one no 2 flood on floor
  - Front room painted in, 2 4x5 negatives; 0207 (Box 9)
    8 counts for lights in lamps; 30 counts while painting in; F 32 stop wide angle lens; used 1 no 2 flood to paint; find shot painted; no lights in lamps
  - Janette Saucy rigs up a clever way to feed her motherless registered Duroc pigs, beer bottles filled with warm milk and an especially constructed trough, pigs are doing fine; at Saucy farm, Salem, Oregon, 0208; 2 prints and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
    1/100 F22; s.p.; s. pan press; flash at camera; 4 counts F8 K3
  - Neil Hagedorn with Sancy's registered 2 week old Duroc pigs, March 13, 1949; 0209; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Bedrooms; test shots, 0212; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Barry and Cherie reaching for soap bubbles, 0213; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    1/25 at F8; photo floods
  - Man walking in snow storm on courthouse lawn, 0214; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Barry and Cherie with candy, 0215; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Cherie tying shoe; less than 2 years old, 0216; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Cherie tying Barry's shoe, 0217; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Barry tying Cheryl's shoe, 0218; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 9)
  - Cherie; hands on cheeks, 0219; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Berg's store; long shot, 0220; print and 2 4x5 negatives (Box 4, 9)
  - Berg's store meat counter, 0221; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Berg's store vegetable counter, 0222; print and 4x5 negative (Box 4, 9)
  - Refrigeration plant at Saucey farm, Salem, Oregon; installed by Richy and Fogy, 0223; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
    flash; 1/50 at F16
  - Cherie and Barry looking at pictures, 0228; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Cherie and Barry, 0230; 4x5 negative (Box 9)
  - Cherie and Barry; Barry blowing bubbles, 0231; 4x5 negative (Box 9)